Guide to the Meyer Library Lecture Tapes ARS.0116
Archive of Recorded Sound
Meyer Library Lecture Tapes
1958-1977
ARS.0116
8 boxes: 277 open reel tapes (65 5" reels; 212 7" reels)
Archive of Recorded Sound
Originally a set of circulating open reel tapes available at Stanford University's J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library. The tapes contain a variety of non-musical material and include lectures by Stanford faculty and class audio reserves (including commercially distributed tapes) of poetry and prose readings, radio broadcasts, speeches, panel discussions and other spoken word recordings.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope and Contents
The Meyer Library Lecture Tapes was originally a circulating set of open reel tape recordings available at Stanford University's J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library. This listening library contains a variety of non-musical material supporting the educational mission of the university and include lectures by Stanford faculty and class audio reserves consisting of poetry and prose readings, radio broadcasts, speeches, panel discussions, and other spoken word recordings (designated as a "ZY" series) and commercially distributed lecture and reading tapes ("ZZ" series). The tapes are numbered and are identified with specific departments, such as Human Biology, English, Communication, Psychology, Music, and History.
Notable faculty lecturers include Carl Djerassi, Diane Middlebrook (teaching a biology class), Sanford Dornbusch, Henry Breitrose, and Philip Zimbardo. From the Music Department, there are lectures from Sandor Salgo, Harold Schmidt, and William Crosten. Among the guest lectures there is a reading on campus by Pablo Neruda in 1971. The commercial releases contain a wide variety of speakers, including such figures as Anaïs Nin, Denise Levertov, Leroi Jones, Sonia Sanchez, Allen Ginsberg, Anthony Burgess, John Barth, and Alan Watts. Publishers include Broadside Voices, Pacifica Tape Library, the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, and the American Association for the Advancement of Science. One highlight of the latter's 1969 annual meeting is a session called Science and Music: Technological Issues and the Music of the Future, hosted by Milton Babbitt. The collection was transferred to the Archive of Recorded Sound at an unknown date.
Related Collections
Related collections at the Archive of Recorded Sound include the Stanford Speech Collection (ARS0022), Stanford Tape Collection (ARS0112), Preservation Master Tape Collection (ARS0097), Stanford Program for Recordings in Sound Collection (ARS0104), and the KZSU collection (ARS0062).
Indexing Terms
Stanford University; Speeches, addresses, etc.
- 1. ZY series [Stanford faculty lectures]
  - Human Biology
    - ZY 3-10. Special lecture series, Spring (April 5th-June 11th) 1976, Human Biology, 8 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
    - ZY 26. Bernfield, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 34. Mathers, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 36. Davidson, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 38. Barchas, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 41. Fuchs, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 42. Lederberg, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 44. Schwartz, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 45. Ebaugh, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 46. Tharpe, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 62. Katchadurian, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 63. Dornbusch, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 64. Djerassi, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 65. Dornbusch, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 66. Hastorf, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 67. Siegel, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 73. Jacklin, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 74. Meyer, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 78. Gurley, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 79. Willis, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 80. Bem, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 83. Corning, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 104. Pittendrigh, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 142. Falcon, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 143. Ingle, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 145. Kennedy, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 222. Kennedy, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 228. Heller, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 230. Washburn, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 232. Sarich, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 245. Greenberg, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 707. Gurley, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 746. Wessels, 1976; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 900. Katchadurian, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 904-908. Lunde, 1977; 5 7" open reel tapes (Audio 4)
    - ZY 909. Karchadurian, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 910. Davidson, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 909, 911-916. Katchadurian, 1977; 7 7" open reel tapes (Audio 5)
    - ZY 917-918. Lunde, 1977; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 5)
    - ZY 919. Laub, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 920. Islas, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 921. Mancall, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 922. Middlebrook, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 923. Elsen, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 925. Hagopian, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 926. Wolfe, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 928. Foley, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 929. Bem, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 930. The erotic in film, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 931. Katchadurian, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Civil Engineering
    - ZY 631. Eliassen, 1969; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Communication
    - ZY 324. Soap operas (original radio broadcasts), 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 325. Radio show (Tom Mix), 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 326. Radio show (Nick Carter, Master Detective), 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 386. Mayer, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 387. Hudson, Radio news, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 436. Dundes, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 680. Breitrose, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 681. Breitrose, Film in Weimar, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 682. Breitrose, German cinema in the 1920s, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 683. Breitrose, French film industry in the 1920s, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 684. Breitrose, US film industry in the 1920s, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 685. Breitrose, American films in the 1930s, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Economics
    - ZY 399. Samuel Bowles Talk. Gurley, Political Economics, 1974; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 470-477. SWOPSI (Stanford Workshops on Political and Social Issues) Symposium, 1972-02; 8 7" open reel tapes (Audio 2)
  - Education
    - ZY 581. Education Colloquium: Thoughts on British and American education, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - English
    - ZY 97. Black Mountain Poetry Reading and Symposium (BBC broadcast), 1972-08-28; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 382. Friedlander, Blues Evolution, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 383. Friedlander, Blues Evolution, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 384. Pablo Neruda lecture and reading, 1971-11-23; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 453. Mark Schorer, 1968-10-30; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 478. Chace. KPFA broadcast on Sylvia Plath, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 1197. Koolish. Women's Poetry Festival, UC (KPFA broadcast), 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 1206. Koolish, 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - French and Italian
    - ZY 543. Claude Simon lecture, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - German
    - ZY 438. Kafka and Sartre, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - History
    - ZY 422. Strong, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 424. Strong, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 491. Potter, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 493. Potter, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 494. Potter, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 495. Potter, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 595-596. Stansky, 1975; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 4)
  - Music
    - ZY 94. Bresnick, 1974; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 95. Bresnick, 1974; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 200. Wolterink, 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 201. Wolterink, 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 204. Salgo, 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - ZY 452. Kuhn, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 484. Schmidt, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 496. Salgo, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 497. Crosten, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 498. Schmidt, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 499. Schmidt, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 506. Tcherepnin, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 507-512. Crosten, Music 11A, 1971; 6 7" open reel tapes (Audio 3)
    - ZY 513. Brindle, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 513. Brindle, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 514-524; 528-535. Schmidt, Music 1, 1969; 16 7" open reel tapes (Audio 3)
    - ZY 515A. Schmidt, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 544. Schmidt, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 547-560. Crosten, Music 11B, 1970; 8 7" open reel tapes (Audio 4)
    - ZY 561. Tcherepnin, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 565. Schmidt, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Psychology
    - ZY 485. Zimbardo, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 486. Jensen discussion, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 568. Kanellokos, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Religious Studies
    - ZY 266. Berman: Allah has spoken (for cello), 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 1212. Berman, 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZY 1217. Berman, 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Sociology
    - ZY 690. Zelditch, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Speech
    - ZY 327. Nixon inaugural address (Speech, Public Speaking), 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 525. Moratorium speeches, 1969-10-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 527. Nixon Vietnam Speech, 1969-11-03; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - Undergraduate Studies
    - ZY 600-601. Katchadurian, 1971; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 4)
  - miscellaneous (no department listed)
    - ZY 266. Hubert Humphrey at Stanford, 1967-02-20; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 374. R.W. Lyman press release, 1970-09-25; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 451. George Wallace at Long Beach, 1967-11-04; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 465. Eulogy for Robert Kennedy, by Senator Edward Kennedy, 1968-10-30; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - ZY 536. Hemes space program (I.E. 100), 1969; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - ZY 537. World Press #24, 1969-11-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - ZY 676. McGovern speech, To End The War (NBC television), 1970-05-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
- 2. ZZ series [commercially-produced readings, meetings, and lectures]
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (136th Meeting, Boston, Mass. December 1969), 1969-12
    - ZZ 146-147. Political Attitudes of Scientists, 1969-12; 2 5" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 148-151. Arms Control and Disarmament, 1969-12; 5 5" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 152-155. Academic Research and the Military, 1969-12; 4 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 156-157. Science and Music (Technological Issues and the Music of the Future), 1969-12; 2 5" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 158-159. Chemical and Biological Warfare, 1969-12; 2 5" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 160-163. Approaches to Policy Sciences, 1969-12; 4 5" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
  - Broadside Voices
    - ZZ 2. James Emanuel. The Treehouse, 1968; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 3. Sonia Sanchez. Homecoming, 1969; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 4. Dudley Randall reading and Jerry Moore singing Poems of Cities Burning, 1968; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 5. Beatrice Murphy and Nancy Arnez read The Rocks Cry Out, 1969; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 6. Etheridge Knight reads Poems From Prison, 1968; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Canadian Writers on Tape (Ontario Institute for Studies in Education), 1971
    - ZZ 387. Mordecai Richler, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 388. Hugh MacLennan, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 389. Sinclair Ross, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 390. Hugh Garner, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 391. Margaret Lawrence, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 392. Morley Callaghan, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions
    - ZZ 127. Hutchins, Douglas. The issues, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 128. Ashby, The future of the university ideal, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 129. Hutchins, On education, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 130. Wilkinson, Anyone for 1984?, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 131. Meiklejohn, Education for freedom, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 132. Ferry, Finn. Schooling vs. Education: Rx for, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 133. A synthesis: university convocation, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 134. Rabi, Pauling, Kerr, Barr, Park. The students and the university, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 135. Lippman, The university and the human condition, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 136. Kerr, Towards a more perfect university, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 137. Park, The idea of community in the university, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 138. Fulbright, Ashmore. The university and the requirements of democracy, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 139. Barzun, The university as beloved republic, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 140. Pike, The crisis in religion, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 269. Schurman, Wheeler, O'Connor. China without poverty, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 270. Schurman. China policy, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 271. Gurley, China: economic development in a human context, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 272. Richman, Cogley. A view from inside China, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 273. Reischauer, Myth of the China menace, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 274. Tompkins, Richman, Mote in the eye, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 275. Eisler, Wheeler. Green revolutions, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 276. Kahin, China obsession, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 359. Walter Millis, The Warless World, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 360. Huxley, The Politics of ecology, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 361. Robert Heilbroner. The Culture Gap in Capitalism, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 362. Harrington, Ferry, Keegan. New utopias, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 363-365. A View of the Economy, 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 366. A World Community - and US Foreign Policy. Excerpts from speeches from the Center's International Convocation on peace, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 367. The "Haves" and the "have-nots", 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 368. United Nations, After "pacem in terris", 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 369. After "Pacem in Terris..: II Members of the UN, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 370. Elisabeth Mann Borgese, A Fish Story for Peace, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 371. Michael Harrington, Capitalism, Socialism and Communism, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 372. A Harvest of Thorns - Readings on war, with music, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 373-377. The Machine Age, 5 7" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
  - McGraw-Hill Sound Seminars
    - ZZ 203. Poetry of James T. Farrell, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 204. Jean Stafford reads one of her short stories, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 205-206. Poetry of Muriel Rukeyser, 2 5" open reel tapes (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 207. Poetry of Wendell Berry, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 208. Poetry readings by Anthony Burgess, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 209. Prose readings by John Barth, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 211. Poetry of William Jay Smith, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 212. Poetry of Robert Lowell, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 213. Poetry of William Dickey, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 214. Poetry of Edward Dahlberg, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 215. Prose and poetry of John Updike, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 216. J. Barth, Two narratives for tape and live voice, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 217. Poetry of Stephen Spender, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 218. William Styron reads from his works, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
  - Pacifica Tape Library
    - ZZ 122. Borgstrom, Are man and nature on a collision course?, 1969; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 123. Brandwein, Now hear this, 1969; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 124. Lowe. Hired Hands, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 125. Ehrlich, The population bomb, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 126. Indians talking about Indians, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - ZZ 178. Poems of Brother Antoninus (KPFA), 1958; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 179-180. Allen Ginsberg reads his poetry, 1963-1966; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 181. Randall Jarrell reads his poetry, 1956; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 182. Four Black Poets, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 183. Anaïs Nin in a dramatic reading from her diary, 1966-05-22; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 184. Kung, The church and sincerity, 1966-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 185. Denise Levertov reads her poems, 1961-11-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 186. Kaufmann, Existentialism: crisis of the new order, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 187-188. Erikson, Identity, 1966-01; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 189. New poetry: James Dickey, 1965; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 190-191. Paul Tillich at Yale, 1959; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 192. Poems of Brother Antonius, 1962-12-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - ZZ 193. Leroi Jones, Gwendolyn Brooks Poetry Reading, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 194. Leroi Jones Poetry Reading (KPFA), 1964-08; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 195-196. Barth, Evangelical theory (WBAI), 1962-04; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 197-198. Music in Communist China, 1963; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 199. Fujimoto, Failure of democracy in a time of crisis, 1968-12; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 200. Ross, Challenge to the concentration camp law, 1969-03-25; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 201. Windmiller, The Japanese in California, 1959-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 262-264. Four black poets, 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 7)
  - Psychology Today (Interviews and sessions from the 80th Annual APA meeting, Hawaii, 1972)
    - ZZ 393. Rogers, Alternatives to marriage, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 394. Gordon, Parent effectiveness training, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 395. Liebert, Television and children, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 396. Shorr, Psycho-imagination therapy, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 397. Campbell, Psychological testing, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 398. Thomas, Black psychology, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 399. Seligman, Learned helplessness, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 400. May, Power and innocence, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - ZZR 401. Zimbardo, Prison reform, 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Alan Watts, Musical Engineering Associates (Sauselito, CA)
    - ZZ 351. Watts, Zen and the limits of explanation, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 352. Watts, Not what might be, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 353. Watts, Power of positive nothingness, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 354. Watts, What is reality?, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 355-357. Watts, Philosophy of meditation, 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
    - ZZ 358. Watts, Introduction to Oriental philosophy, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - miscellaneous
    - ZZ 265-268. Olsen. Berkeley Poetry Conference lecture and reading, 1965-07; 4 7" open reel tapes (Audio 7)
    - ZZ 1. Jon Eckels. Home is where the soul is, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)